There is no doubt that artificial intelligence – or AI – has become an important part of our lives.
毫无疑问，人工智能——或称AI——已成为我们生活的重要组成部分。
It is no longer just a thing of science fiction: it's an incredible technological breakthrough that has changed the way we live.
它不再只是科幻小说中的事物：这是一项令人难以置信的技术突破，改变了我们的生活方式。
But there are fears that AI has become too intelligent and could be a threat to humanity.
但也有人担心，AI已经变得过于智能，可能对人类构成威胁。
This claim might sound extreme, but a letter signed by more than 1,000 technology experts, including Tesla boss Elon Musk, called on the world to press pause on the development of more advanced AI because of the risks.
这种说法可能听起来有些极端，但一封由包括特斯拉老板埃隆·马斯克在内的1000多名技术专家签署的信件，呼吁全球因潜在的风险而暂停更先进AI的开发。
Estonian billionaire Jaan Tallinn, for example, who helped develop communication app Skype, thinks we should be cautious.
例如，帮助开发通讯应用Skype的爱沙尼亚亿万富翁扬·塔林认为我们应该保持谨慎。
And The Future of Life Institute, a not-for-profit organisation, says that there should be a temporary pause in advanced AI development, saying that "AI systems with human-competitive intelligence can pose profound risks to society and humanity."
非营利组织"未来生命研究所"表示，应该暂时停止高级AI的开发，称"具有与人类竞争智能的AI系统可能对社会和人类构成巨大风险。"
This pessimistic outlook is supported by a report by investment bank Goldman Sachs that says AI could replace the equivalent of 300 million full-time jobs.
这种悲观的看法得到了投资银行高盛的一份报告的支持，该报告称AI可能取代相当于3亿个全职工作岗位。
But it may also mean new jobs and a productivity boom.
但这也可能意味着新的就业机会和生产力的繁荣。
We may argue that AI such as chatbots can help us.
我们可能会说，像聊天机器人这样的AI可以帮助我们。
State-of-the-art ChatGPT, for example, has been helping some students write assignments.
例如，最先进的ChatGPT一直在帮助一些学生写作业。
AI is allowing computers to think or act in a more human way.
AI使计算机能够以更像人类的方式思考或行动。
And machine learning means computers can learn what to do without being given explicit instructions.
而机器学习意味着计算机可以在没有明确指令的情况下学习该做什么。
The technology is impressive, but as it starts to think for itself, will it outsmart us?
这项技术令人印象深刻，但随着它开始独立思考，它会比我们更聪明吗？
Some people are more optimistic.
有些人则更为乐观。
AI advocates say the tech is already delivering real social and economic benefits for people.
AI的倡导者表示，这项技术已经在为人们带来实际的社会和经济效益。
Meanwhile, the founder of Microsoft, Bill Gates, has called on governments to work with industry to "limit the risks" of AI.
与此同时，微软创始人比尔·盖茨呼吁各国政府与行业合作，以"限制AI的风险"。
But he says the technology could save lives, particularly in poorer countries.
但他表示，这项技术可以拯救生命，尤其是在较贫穷的国家。
He says, "Just as the world needs its brightest people focused on its biggest problems, we will need to focus the world's best AIs on its biggest problems."
他说："正如世界需要最聪明的人专注于最大的问题一样，我们也需要将世界上最好的AI专注于最大的问题。"
If this happens, maybe humanity will have a future.
如果这种情况发生，也许人类将拥有未来。